<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Shikhar Kanaskar</title>
    <link>https://shikharkanaskar.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shikhar Kanaskar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://shikharkanaskar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://shikharkanaskar.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shikharkanaskar.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently pursuing Master of Science in Business Analytics and Information Management at Purdue University. I am a Highly motivated individual with 3+ years of experience in data science, specialized in solving unstructured business problems using machine learning &amp;amp; statistics.
For last 3 to 4 years, I have been solving various real-world problems using data-driven solutions.
SKILLS •	Programming: Python (Pandas, Spark, Numpy, TensorFlow, Keras, pytorch, Scikit-learn), SQL, SAS Enterprise Miner, R, C++ •	Certifications: AWS Cloud Practitioner, Tableau Desktop Specialist, Six Sigma Green Belt, AI / ML Specialist (Simplilearn) •	Machine Learning &amp;amp; Analytics: Linear &amp;amp; Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Random Forest, SVM, K-Means, Gradient Boosting, CNN, ANN, LSTM, Time Series Forecasting (ARIMA), Predictive Modeling, MS-Excel •	Databases / Big Data: AWS Redshift, Databricks, Snowflake, Google Cloud Platform and Azure •	Organizational Skills: Project management, Analytical Problem Solving, Creative, Written and Communication Skills</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certifications</title>
      <link>https://shikharkanaskar.com/certifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shikharkanaskar.com/certifications/</guid>
      <description> AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Tableau Desktop Specialist Machine Learning Advanced Certification Training Six Sigma Green Belt Certified </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://shikharkanaskar.com/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shikharkanaskar.com/posts/</guid>
      <description>Here is a collection of articles around my personal life and adventures.
7 things you realize on your first trek — Kedarkantha. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://shikharkanaskar.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shikharkanaskar.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Some of my personal projects in data science.
Text and Image Classification for Craigslist using GloVe and MobileNet — Transfer Learning Forecasting Stock Prices: using ARIMA, Fourier Transformation and Deep Learning Go-To-Market Strategy for a Banking Firm to expand their Mortgage Loan Operations: Using clustering algorithms to identify target customers Application of SAS EM for Machine Learning: Firm Collapse Prediction Pharmaceutical Sales Rep call optimization using Graph Theory, Kmeans Clustering and Prediction of Prescription Conversion using XGBoost Mercedes-Benz Greener Manufacturing Loan Risk Prediction </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://shikharkanaskar.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shikharkanaskar.com/resume/</guid>
      <description> Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page: / Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page: / </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
